costco.co.uk 2015-05-12

# Costco UK - Your Rights

## Privacy Policy Last updated 07/05/2015

This privacy statement (also referred to as Costco's Online Privacy Policy) explains our privacy practices for our Members and customers who shop in our UK warehouse stores or use our website: www.costco.co.uk. We draw your attention to the fact that this policy does not apply to Costco’s [Online Digital Photo Centre](http://warehouses.costco.co.uk/privacy/).

#### Costco's Commitment to Privacy

We respect your right to privacy. We maintain and use your Personal Data in accordance with applicable laws, including the Data Protection Act of 1998. We do not sell, rent, share or disclose Personal Data to third parties without your prior consent, except in the circumstances described in this Privacy Statement. In addition, your ability to make informed choices about the uses of your information is important to us. This privacy statement explains our policy regarding the collection, use, disclosure and protection of Personal Data. The links below provide detailed information about our privacy practices:

A. What is Personal Data?  
B. Collection of Personal Data  
C. Use of Personal Data by Costco  
D. Sharing of Personal Data  
 1\. Order Fulfilment  
 2\. Service Providers and Contractors  
 3\. Primary Costco Account Holder  
 4\. Services  
E. Cross-Border Transfers   
F. Other Uses and Disclosures   
G. Protection of Personal and Credit Card Information   
H. Choice; Updating Your Account Data   
I. Optical and Hearing Centres   
J. Cookies and Online Specifics   
 1\. Cookies; Links and Accessing Costco via a Mobile Device  
 2\. Links to Other Sites  
 3\. Accessing Costco on your Mobile Device  
K. Use of the Costco.co.uk Site by Minors   
L. Questions or Concerns   
M. Changes to this Statement

#### A. What is Personal Data?

Personal Data is information that identifies an individual or that can be reasonably associated with a specific person or entity, such as a name, contact information, telephone number, Internet (IP) address and information about an individual’s purchases and online shopping. Personal information also includes medical information collected through our pharmacies, hearing aid centers and optical centers (see Health Care Centers below). As a convenience to our Members, we allow the primary cardholder to add his/her spouse or others to a membership account.

#### B. Collection of Personal Data

We collect the Personal Data that you provide us, such as when you: 

  * Sign up for or renew your Costco membership
  * Register to use Costco.co.uk or consent to receive news about specials or other promotions;
  * Place an order or purchase products or services, at our warehouse stores or online;
  * Contact us for any reason;
  * Sign up for or renew your Costco membership or online subscription;
  * Sign up for or participate in our various Services (see Services below).

We may automatically collect some information when you visit our website, such as your computer's IP address or your device ID and operating system, the site from which you linked to us, your site activity, the time and date of your visit, and your purchases. This information may be collected through the use of "cookies" and web beacons (see Cookies below). We also receive information from third parties who help us correct our records, prevent fraud, and provide Services (see Services below) or special promotions or products. We may combine any of this information with the other Personal Data we maintain about you.

#### C. Use of Personal Data by Costco

The Personal Data we collect is generally used to process your requests or transactions, provide you with high-quality service, tell you about opportunities we think will be of interest and administer your account, including distribution of our own surveys and publications. For example, we may: 

  * Alert you about product recalls or safety issues;
  * Send notifications (via email or SMS/text message) related to your purchases, such as purchase confirmations or delivery schedules;
  * If you consent to receive it, provide you with promotional information, such as coupons, offers and product recommendations ("Promotional Information"). You may contact us at any time to decline Promotional Information (see Choice below).

#### D. Sharing of Personal Data

We share information in these circumstances: 

  1. **Order Fulfilment**  
We may provide to a third party information necessary to process a transaction or fulfil an order you have placed with us. However, we give suppliers, and others involved in the distribution chain only the information needed to provide you the products or services you order, and we require them to keep the information confidential and not to use it for other purposes. We are not responsible for any information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them.

  2. **Service Providers and Contractors**  
We may contract with others to perform services on our behalf. For example, we retain companies to process debit and credit card payments, ship merchandise, manage our customer care centre, distribute emails, process rebates or analyse and correct or update our data. If any of these service providers need access to your Personal Data, we require them to use it only to perform the services for us. We also require that they maintain the confidentiality of the information and/or return the information to us when they no longer need it.

  3. **Primary Costco Account Holder**

If you are a Costco Member, each membership account has an individual primary account holder who is authorised to designate and remove add-on members and make other account management decisions. We may disclose Personal Data that relates to activities occurring under the account to the primary account holder.

Similarly each online subscription account has a primary Subscriber. We may disclose Personal Data that relates to activities occurring under the account to the Subscriber of record.

  4. **Services**

You may purchase products and services offered by us through third parties, such as financial, travel, insurance and other business and consumer services ("Services"). We may share your name, postal address, email address and membership or subscriber status, number and type ("Information") with these third parties so they may notify you of their offerings, to determine whether, or at what level, you qualify for the products, offerings or services, and to evaluate new and existing products, offerings or services. If you prefer that we do not share Information with these third parties, you can contact us at any time (see Choice below).

If you purchase, apply for or request Services, information you provide will be shared directly with the third party offering the Services.

These third parties are required to use Personal Data we share only to provide the requested Services. We are not responsible for any additional information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their privacy practices and policies before disclosing information to them. Information you provide to third parties, may in turn be shared with us along with information about your use of the services. In some cases, these third parties may require as a condition of providing services to you that you authorise them to share information with us. If we terminate our relationship with a third party, information you provided to them may be returned to us, and we may provide that information to a new third party offering the same or similar services.

If you apply for an American Express Card through Costco Wholesale, Costco Wholesale will collect the application on behalf of American Express.

#### E. Cross-Border Transfers

In some cases Personal Data may be transferred outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) in order to carry out processes, including but not limited to e-mail communications and customer call-centre services. Costco ensures that Personal Data transferred outside the EEA is maintained with at least the same level of security and protection for the rights and freedoms of data subjects that is required under the UK Data Protection Act of 1998. By submitting Personal Data to us you consent to the transfer and storage of your personal data outside the EEA.

#### F. Other Uses and Disclosures

In addition, we may use or disclose Personal Data in the good faith belief that we are lawfully authorised to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to protect you, to comply with legal process or authorities, to respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of the Costco Companies, our shoppers, Costco’s Members and Subscribers, our employees or the public. This includes disclosure of information to control or investigate fraud. Personal Data, may be disclosed or transferred as part of, or during negotiations of, any merger or sale of company assets or acquisition.

#### G. Protection of Personal and Credit Card Information

We have physical, administrative and technical security measures in place to protect Personal Data from loss, misuse or alteration while it is under our control. When you enter Personal Data online, that information is encrypted prior to transmission using a security protocol called SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). We also use SSL to allow you to securely view your online account and registration information. Even if you establish an account with us, we do not retain your credit card information. A unique “token” is substituted for your credit card number. If you become a repeat customer, you may be asked to create a password that you will give us instead of your credit card number, providing an additional layer of security.

Online account information is accessible only by using a password. You must keep your password confidential. You are responsible for all uses of www.costco.co.uk by anyone using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused.

#### H. Choice; Updating Your Account Data

We give you choices related to your personal information, and numerous methods to inform us of your decision. Your choice to opt-out will not apply to your spouse and any add-on members.

We will not send you promotional emails or SMS (text) messages unless you explicitly consent to receive them. If you wish to give or withdraw your consent or update your online account information, or if you have questions concerning our information practices, you may call our Customer Care Centre on Freehone **0800 0324 324** , or access "My Account" if you are a registered user of costco.co.uk.

Your choice not to receive promotional materials means that we also will not share your information with our providers of Services.

If you have more than one email address, you will need to make separate privacy elections for each. If you receive emails from the online Photo Center or have separately opted to receive materials from one of our Services providers (see Services) you will need to change your privacy elections separately for these communications as well.

#### I. Optical and Hearing Centres

If you purchase eyeglasses, contact lens, hearing devices and accessories from us, we collect and retain in our files your prescription information as well as a limited amount of background health information that you give us so that we may properly provide the service and/or medical device you have requested. We have extraordinary procedures in place to protect your health-related information. If you request or receive NHS funding for optical or hearing devices or services, we may share your health information with the NHS.

#### J. Cookies and Online Specifics

  1. **Cookies; Links and Accessing Costco via a Mobile Device.**

Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer. They enable us to monitor online activity. When you first access the website, you will be asked if you consent to our use of cookies. If you do not consent, the web site will not load properly.

Like most web sites, we use cookies to log your IP address, identify your browser type, and log the date and time of your purchases and other activities. We use this information for system administration, troubleshooting, fraud investigation, communications from Costco (only) and optimising your shopping experience. For example, we may customise our home page for you, better display pages according to your browser type, and/or deliver customised product recommendations and email. Cookies are not spyware, and Costco does not collect multi- site data or, with the exception of Google Analytics, share information with others that we gather through cookies.

We share your IP address, but no other Personal Data, with Google Analytics in order to obtain data about how our website is accessed and used. If you do not wish your IP address to be tracked for this purpose, you may opt-out of Google Analytics by following the steps found at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Finally, we use web beacons to determine when and how many times a page has been viewed. Again, we use this information for our own marketing purposes.

If you would like help clearing cookies, please call our Customer Care Centre on Freephone **0800 0324 324**. If you clear cookies you will need to accept our cookie policy upon your next visit to our website.

  2. **Links to Other Sites**

From our web site you can link to websites of third parties who we allow to offer goods, information and/or Services. If it is not clear from the context that you are being directed to a third party site, we endeavour to notify you that you are visiting a site where a different privacy policy applies. In general, any Personal Data you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of websites to which we link. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with Personal Data.

  3. **Accessing Costco on Your Mobile Device**

Before we collect or send location –specific information, we will ask for your consent. You may use our apps or mobile site without consenting to this, and you may withdraw your consent by changing your selection within the app. Your general consent to your mobile service provider to allow (or disallow) location-based services does not automatically apply to us.

In general, you do not need to provide any personal information to connect with us via your mobile device. If you wish to make a purchase, however, you must create an account. Personal information you provide is subject to this Privacy Policy. In addition, as with any online service, our apps and mobile site automatically collect information such as an IP address, the unique identifier of your mobile device and the URL from which you accessed our app (see Online Specifics). Neither your name nor telephone number are automatically collected. It is not possible to opt out of providing information automatically collected through our apps.

Providers who supply the technology necessary for us to provide the app may share in the receipt of automatically collected information. We restrict their use of Personal Information to the purpose of providing services to Costco. In addition, you should review the privacy statements published by your mobile carrier and by your device manufacturer. Either or both of them also may automatically collect information. Costco does not have access to information you provide to or that is automatically collected by these third parties.

Our apps and mobile site may provide links to Costco service providers (see [Member Services](http://warehouses.costco.co.uk/membership/services/)) and other third parties (see Links to Other Sites).

#### K. Use of costco.co.uk Website by Minors

We encourage parents to take an active interest in their children's use of the Internet. We do not intend to collect information from minors. If you are under 18, you should not provide information on the costco.co.uk website.

#### L. Questions or Concerns

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy statement or would like to contact us for any reason, you can call our Customer Care Centre on freephone **0800 0324 324** or see Contact Us.

#### M. Changes to this Statement

We may change this privacy statement at any time, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating at the top of the privacy statement the date it was last updated. We encourage you to review our privacy statement to make sure you understand how your Personal Data will be used. If we make a material change to how we use Personal Data and the new uses are unrelated to uses we disclose in this statement, we will communicate the changes in advance.

## Payment Security

We have put into place technical, contractual, administrative and physical security measures in an effort to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse or alteration while it is under our control. Personal information we collect is stored electronically and may be combined with other information.

We also use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input during online transactions. SSL Certificate details can be found by clicking the padlock icon next to the URL. We may request proof of identity before we disclose Personal Information to you in conjunction with our security procedures.

In some cases, Personal Information may be transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA) in order to carry out essential processes. Costco.co.uk ensures that at all times Personal Information transferred outside the EEA is maintained with at least the same level of security that is required in the UK. By submitting Personal Information to costco.co.uk you consent to the transfer and storage of your Personal Information outside the EEA. For further information please refer to our Privacy Policy.

## Conditions of use Last updated 18/04/2013

These Terms and Conditions apply to the use of www.costco.co.uk (the “website”) and our sale and supply of goods and services via this website.

The website is the property of Costco Online UK Limited (“Costco”), which provides you access and use of this website subject to your compliance with these Terms and Conditions and all related policies and terms (collectively, the "Site Terms"). The Site Terms include, but are not limited to, the Privacy Policy and the Delivery, Cancellations and Assistance Policy. Please review these Terms and Conditions and all related policies and terms before using this website.

By using and accessing the website you agree to be bound by the Site Terms and all applicable law. You consented to these Site Terms the first time you accessed this website from a particular computer or device, and confirm your consent each time you use this website.

If you do not have the authority to agree to or accept these Site Terms, you may not use or access this website.

The links below provide detailed information about our Site Terms. Please read them carefully:

A. SHOPPING WWW.COSTCO.CO.UK: THREE OPTIONS   
B. RELATED POLICIES AND TERMS   
C. MODIFICATION OF SITE TERMS    
D. LIMITATIONS ON USAGE, LICENCE AND WEBSITE ACCESS    
E. CONTRACT PRICING, FORMATION AND PAYMENT    
F. PRODUCT DESCRIPTIONS AND AVAILABILITY, PRICE INDICATIONS AND OFFERS AND CHANGES   
G. PASSWORDS AND SECURITY   
H. INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY   
   a. Ownership  
   b. Trade marks  
   c. Restrictions on use  
I. SOFTWARE   
J. HYPERLINKS   
   a. Links to the website  
   b. Third Party Links  
K. YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES; INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US; ENFORCEMENT   
L. MINORS   
M. DISCLAIMERS   
N. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY   
O. GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION   
Q. TERMINATION   
R. SEVERABILITY AND WAIVERS   
S. THIRD PARTY RIGHTS   
T. FURTHER INFORMATION    
U. CONTACT US

#### DEFINITIONS AND INTERPRETATION

In the Site Terms: 

"Consumer" means an individual who uses the website to purchase goods or services from us that are not related to their trade, business or profession;

"Cookies" are small text files stored on your computer.

"Costco Companies" means the group of companies of which we are part, which currently includes Costco Wholesale Corporation, Price Costco International, Inc. and Costco Wholesale UK Limited;

"Costco Member" means a trade or individual member of any of the warehouse club membership programmes operated by the Costco Companies or their affiliates;

"Costco Satisfaction Guarantee" means the Costco satisfaction guarantee set out in the Consumer Delivery, Cancellation, Replacement and Returns Policies;

"Higher Value Goods" means goods of which the price per unit to Costco Members described on the website (exclusive of VAT and delivery charges) exceeds £1000;

’Personal Data’ means data that identifies an individual or that can be reasonably associated with a specific person or entity, such as a name, contact information, telephone number, Internet (IP) address, and information about an individual’s purchases and online shopping;

"Site Materials" means all materials on the website including, but without limitation to, trade marks, design, product description, HTML text, graphics, other files, photographs, codes, software layout, designs forms and the selection and arrangement thereof;

"Subscriber" means an individual who pays an annual subscription fee in order to shop on www.costco.co.uk but who is not a current Costco Member.

’We’ or ’us’ or "Costco" means Costco Online UK Limited. In the Site Terms, paragraph headings are used for convenience only. They are not intended to describe the entire content of the paragraphs or have any effect on their interpretation.

#### A. SHOPPING WWW.COSTCO.CO.UK: THREE OPTIONS

We offer three ways to shop:

**Costco Members:** If you are a Costco Member you may shop online by entering your member number at checkout. As a Costco Member you do not pay any surcharge on website purchases. If you are an Executive Member your online purchases qualify toward your annual reward. [Find out to see if you qualify for membership](http://www.warehouses.costco.co.uk/membership/).

**Subscribers:** You may become a Costco Online Subscriber. When you make your first purchase, at checkout you may opt to subscribe by paying an annual fee. Subscribers do not pay any surcharge on website purchases. When making your first purchase after expiry, you will be given an oppportunity to renew your subscription for an additional year. Subscribers must be eighteen years of age or older.

**Surcharge:** If you are neither a Costco Member nor a Subscriber, you may shop www.Costco.co.uk by paying a 5% surcharge on all purchases. This charge will be added automatically to your purchase at check-out.

If you are not satisfied with your subscription, we will refund your entire subscription fee at any time. The five percent surcharge similarly is refundable to the same extent as the corresponding merchandise.

#### B. RELATED POLICIES AND TERMS

Additional Site Terms apply to use of this website and our sale/supply of goods and services. These include:

  * Costco Online Privacy Policy
  * Returns and Cancellation & Assistance Procedures
  * WEEE terms, relating to applicable purchases of electrical and electronic equipment
  * [For Costco Wholesale Members only, the provisions of the Membership Terms that apply to them](http://warehouses.costco.co.uk/terms/)

Certain other, or amended, terms apply in the case of particular goods or services, where indicated elsewhere in the Site Terms or in the relevant part of the website.

Please review all relevant additional Site Terms. The Site Terms do not alter, in any way, the terms or conditions of any other agreement you may have with us or with other Costco Companies for products, services or otherwise. In particular, we draw your attention to the Costco Wholesale Privacy Policy applicable to Costco Members that you should refer to in order to fully understand how we collect, use and otherwise process your Personal Data. In addition, these Terms and Conditions do not apply to Costco’s Online Digital Photo Centre. 

#### C. MODIFICATION OF SITE TERMS

We reserve the right to modify these Site Terms at our sole discretion from time to time and only we have the right to do so. You may not alter, exclude or add to the Site Terms, and any attempt to do so shall have no effect. If the Site Terms are changed, we will post the new terms on the website and note the date they were last updated. Any changes or modification will be effective upon posting of the Site Terms as revised. Your use of the website following the posting will constitute your acceptance of the new Site Terms. However, any changes to the Site Terms will not affect the terms of any order you have already placed for goods or services via this website prior to such posting.

#### D. LIMITATIONS ON USAGE, LICENCE AND WEBSITE ACCESS

This website may only be used to order goods and services for delivery to addresses in the UK. The use of this website is governed by the laws of England and Wales. The laws of your jurisdiction may be more or less strict than the laws that apply to this website. If you access this website from outside the UK you do so at your own risk and are responsible for compliance with the laws of your jurisdiction.

To register and shop with this website you must be eighteen years of age or over. Please refer to Section K for more information in relation to the use of this website by minors.

If you meet the above requirements, we grant you a limited licence to make personal use only of the website. Such grant does not include, without limitation: (a) any resale or commercial use of this website or any Site Materials (defined above); (b) modification, adaptation, translation, reverse engineering, de-compilation, disassembly or conversion into human readable form any of the Site Materials not intended to be so read, including use of or directly viewing the underlying HTML or other code from this website except as interpreted and displayed in a web browser; (c) copying, imitating, mirroring, reproducing, distributing, publishing, downloading, displaying, performing, posting or transmitting any Site Materials (including any trade marks) in any form or by any means, including, but not limited to, electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or otherwise; (d) the collection and use of any product listings or descriptions; (e) making modifications to or other derivative uses of the website and any Site Materials; or (f) use of any data mining, bots, spiders, automated tools or similar data gathering and extraction methods, directly or indirectly, on the Site Materials or to collect any information from the website or any other user of the website. Except as noted above, you are not granted any right or licence by implication, estoppel, or otherwise in or under a patent, trademark, copyright, database right or other Intellectual Property right belonging to the Costco Companies or any third party. You may not use any meta-tags or any other ’hidden text’ utilising any name, trade mark, or product name of the Costco Companies without our express written consent. We may terminate this licence, your subscription and/or your use of or access to the website at any time if you breach or permit any breach of these Site Terms. Such actions by you may also breach applicable laws, including but without limitation to: copyright laws, trademark laws, communications, regulations and statutes. We reserve the right to enforce our legal rights.

#### E. CONTRACT PRICING, FORMATION, PAYMENT AND NON-MEMBER SURCHARGE

Prices indicated on the website include UK mainland delivery charges (unless stated otherwise). However, prices on the website do not include the annual subscription fee or the surcharge that must be paid by customers other than Costco Subscribers and Members when ordering goods or services from us. The surcharge is equal to 5% (five percent) of the total price of the goods and services placed in an order, excluding any VAT charged in respect of those goods and services. Subscription fees and surcharges are subject to VAT, which must be paid in addition. Costco Members whose membership is current and valid at the date of their orders, and who have entered their membership number during the registration process in the My Account section of the website, do not have to pay the surcharge. Subscription fees and surcharges will be separately itemized in the checkout section on the website and added to the price of the goods and services.

Nothing in these Site Terms or elsewhere on this website constitutes an offer to sell or supply goods or services, including a subscription to costco.co.uk. Your order of goods or services or application for a subscription account constitutes an offer to purchase them. Our Order Confirmation confirms the receipt of your order, but does not constitute an acceptance of it.

Except in the case of Higher Value Goods, we accept your order when we despatch the goods or begin to supply the services that you have ordered. This concludes the contract of sale for the goods despatched, but not for any other goods or services that you may have ordered at the same time.

In the case of Higher Value Goods, the contract between Costco and you for the sale/purchase of the goods concerned will not take place until the goods are made available for your inspection at the delivery address you have specified, and you have signed a receipt provided by the carrier. If you choose not to sign the receipt, we will retain the goods in question and your offer to purchase them will be deemed withdrawn.

Title to goods that you order will not pass to you until we have received payment in full for the goods concerned and the goods are delivered to you. We reserve our rights to retain the goods, or recover them from you, at any time until you have paid in full. The risk of loss of or damage to goods that you order will pass to you at the same time as title passes.

We shall be under no liability for any delay or failure to deliver goods or services ordered via this website if the delay or failure is caused by circumstances beyond our reasonable control.

We welcome Visa, MasterCard, Maestro and American Express credit cards. When you order goods from us, you will need to complete your credit or debit card details. We will usually pre-authorize charges for up to ten days prior to shipment, but we will not take payment until shipment. In the case of Higher Value Items, payment may be taken at or about the time that the sale/purchase contract is concluded (as indicated above). 

All card payments are subject to authorisation by your card issuer. If your payment is not authorised, or for any other reason we are not able to take payment when we attempt to do so, we will not fulfil your order. We reserve the right to refuse a subscription to any applicant, and we may revoke a subscription at any time with or without cause.

#### F. PRODUCT DESCRIPTIONS AND AVAILABILITY, PRICE INDICATIONS AND OFFERS AND CHANGES

We take reasonable precautions to ensure that goods and services are fairly and accurately described on our website and that they are available at the prices listed. However, please note that, subject to applicable law, we: (a) reserve the right to change the goods and services advertised or offered for sale through this website without any prior notice, the prices or specifications of such goods and services, and any promotional offers and any other Site Materials at any time and from time to time without any notice or liability to you or any other person; (b) cannot guarantee that goods or services advertised or offered for sale on this website will be available when ordered or thereafter; (c) reserve the right to limit quantities sold or made available for sale; (d) do not warrant that the Site Materials (including but without limitation to product descriptions, photographs and product user guides) are accurate, complete, reliable, current or error-free; and (e) reserve the right not to process orders, and to revise orders or recover funds where the price or other material information on this website is inaccurate or when we recognise there has been a material error or breach of the Site Terms. If we do not process an order for such reason, we will advise you that the order has been cancelled and will either not charge you or will apply credit to the payment type used in the order.

For more information please see our Returns, Cancellations and Assistance Procedures.

#### G. PASSWORDS AND SECURITY

If you use a password to access this website or any portion of it, then you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of the password and for restricting access to your computer. If you use a shared computer, remember to sign-out once you finish shopping at costco.co.uk. In the event that the confidentiality of your account or password is compromised in any manner, you must immediately notify our Customer Care Centre on our freephone number **0800 0324 324**.

We reserve the right to take any and all action as necessary or reasonable to maintain the security of the website and your account, including but without limitation to: terminating your account, changing your password or requesting information to authorise or cancel transactions on your account.

While we take prudent steps to protect your account and the website, we cannot protect your information outside of the website. For example, if we communicate with you electronically but outside of the website, you acknowledge that the communication may not be transmitted and/or stored securely, and may be viewed by others. You acknowledge that by requesting information by e-mail, we may transmit it to you and store it in an unencrypted form. Similarly e-mails you send to us may also be unencrypted, and thus may be viewed by others. We may rely on the authority of anyone accessing your account or using your password. You accept responsibility for their activities. In no event will we be held liable to you for any liabilities or damages resulting from or arising out of (i) any action or inaction of costco.co.uk under this provision; (ii) any compromise of the confidentiality of your account or password, and (iii) any unauthorised access to your account or use of your password.

Please see our Privacy Policy for more information on how we use, collect, store and disclose personal information.

#### H. INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY

a. Ownership

All Site Materials are owned by us or other Costco Companies, and are protected by UK and international copyright, trade mark and other intellectual property laws.

b. Trade marks

COSTCO, COSTCO.CO.UK, KIRKLAND SIGNATURE (and other registered trade marks owned by Costco listed on the attached Exhibit A), and their respective designs and logos are either trade marks or registered trade marks of Costco Companies and may not be copied, imitated or used, in whole or in part, without our prior written permission of costco.co.uk.

In addition all page headers, custom graphics, button icons and scripts are trade marks of Costco and may not be copied, imitated, or used, in whole or in part, without our prior written permission. All other trade marks, registered trade marks, product names and company names or logos mentioned herein or on this website are the property of their respective owners.

c. Restrictions on Use

Except as stated in the Site Terms, none of the materials and Intellectual Property described in these Site Terms may be copied, reproduced, distributed, republished, downloaded, displayed, posted or transmitted in any form or by any means, including, but not limited to, electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or otherwise, without our prior written permission or the respective intellectual property rights owner.

You may electronically copy and print portions of this website for the sole purpose of using materials it contains for informational and non-commercial, personal use only. Any other use of the materials in this website, including any commercial use, reproduction for purposes other than described above, modification, distribution, republication, display, or performance without our prior written permission is strictly prohibited.

#### I. SOFTWARE

Any software, including any files, images incorporated in or generated by the software, and data accompanying the software (collectively “Software”), that may be made available on this website is licensed to you on a non-exclusive and limited basis. The Costco Companies shall retain full and complete title and all intellectual property rights to Software. You shall not copy, distribute, sell, modify, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble or create modified copyright works or other derivative works from any Software.

#### J. HYPERLINKS

a. Links to the website

You are granted a limited, non-exclusive right to create a hypertext link to the home page only of this website, provided such link does not portray any of the Costco Companies or any of their products and services in a false, misleading, derogatory, or otherwise defamatory manner. This limited right may be revoked at any time. You may not use, frame or utilise framing techniques to enclose any Costco trade mark, logo or other proprietary information of the Costco Companies, including the images found at this website, the content of any text or the layout/design of any page, or form contained on a page without our express written consent. All other linking is prohibited without our prior consent. Except as noted above, you are not conveyed any right or licence by implication, estoppel, or otherwise to any patent, trade mark, copyright, design right, database right or other intellectual property right of the Costco Companies or any third party.

b. Third Party Links

We provide links and access to third party websites who we allow to offer goods, information and/or services. We do not monitor or assume responsibility for the content of third parties' statements or websites. Accordingly, we do not endorse or adopt these websites or any information they contain. We make no representations or warranties whatsoever regarding, such third party websites and accept no responsibility for the quality, content, nature, accuracy or reliability of websites accessible by hyperlink from this website or otherwise linked to this website.

#### K. YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES; INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US; ENFORCEMENT

If you become a Subscriber and/or register on this website, you agree that any information you provide to us will be current, accurate and complete. You must inform us of any changes to that information by updating your personal registration details on this website.

In addition, you agree not to use the website to: (1) Engage in or encourage a criminal offence, breachthe rights of any party, or otherwise create liability or breach any national, or international law; (2) Impersonate any person or entity or otherwise misrepresent your affiliation with a person or entity; and (3) Disseminate any harmful content of any kind, including without limitation, viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time bombs, zombies, bots or any other computer programming routines that may damage, spy-on, interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, programme, data or Personal Data controlled or possessed by Costco.co.uk.

All access to and use of this website is governed by and subject to the Site Terms. We have the right, but not the obligation, to monitor any activity and content associated with forums and interactive areas on this website. We may access at any time and use internally for any lawful purpose information stored on our systems, including the content of any e-mails or other communications. Consistent with our Privacy Statement and the Data Protection Act of 1998, we may disclose such information to any third party including law enforcement agencies to protect our rights, property or staff in response to legal process, or in a good faith belief that such disclosure is justified or required in an emergency situation.

We may investigate any reported breach of our Site Terms or complaints and take any action that we deem appropriate. We have the right, but not the obligation, to carry out this process. We can carry out such actions, including but not limited to: issue a warning, suspend or terminate your access and use of the website and related services at any time. Costco takes no responsibility and assumes no liability for any Content posted or uploaded by any third party, or for any mistakes, defamation, slander, libel, omissions, falsehoods, obscenity, pornography or profanity you may encounter on this website.

a. **Responsibility for your Conduct**

You agree to indemnify and hold harmless Costco and its employees, agents and representatives from any claim, action or demand claiming loss, or damages (including legal fees) made or incurred by any third party arising out of or relating to your use of the website, your breach of any Site Terms or of any rights of a third party. Indirect or attempted breaches of these Site Terms or any policy, and actual or attempted breaches by a third party on behalf of a user of this website will be considered breaches of these Site Terms by such user.

#### L. MINORS

We do not knowingly permit any person under 18 years of age to use this website. If you are under 18 years of age, you must not attempt to order goods or submit Personal Data via this website or otherwise use this website.

#### M. DISCLAIMERS 

This website and the materials provided on it are provided on an "as is" basis and, to the extent permitted by applicable law, without warranties of any kind, either express or implied. Costco disclaims, to the extent permitted by applicable law, all warranties, conditions and terms express or implied, including, but not limited to, any warranties that might be implied as to the compatibility of the website with your computer equipment, software or telecommunications links, or as to the fitness for any particular purpose of the website or the content on the website. Costco does not represent or warrant that the website will be available, that the website services will meet your requirements or that materials in this website are accurate, complete, reliable, current, or error-free. Costco is not responsible for typographical errors or omissions relating to pricing, text or photography. Costco does not represent or warrant that this website or its server(s) are free of viruses or other harmful components, even if Costco or its authorised representatives have been advised of the possibility of such viruses or other harmful components and you are advised to use up-to-date commercially available virus screening software when accessing or otherwise using this website. You expressly agree that use of this website, including all content, data or software, distributed by, downloaded or accessed from or through this website is at your sole risk.

Reference to any products, services, processes, or other information, by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, supplier, or otherwise does not constitute or imply endorsement, sponsorship or recommendation thereof by Costco.

#### N. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY 

Please see our Returns and Cancellations Procedures for details of the Costco Satisfaction Guarantee. Nothing in this section affects your rights under the Costco Satisfaction Guarantee or your statutory rights including, but not limited to, your statutory cancellation rights. For further information on Consumer statutory rights, please see Section S (Further Information) below or Statutory Rights section.

Except to the extent that applicable law may prohibit the exclusion of such liability, Costco shall have no liability for any direct, special, punitive, exemplary, indirect or consequential losses, liabilities, costs (including legal costs), expenses or damages of any kind (collectively, "loss and damage"), including but not limited to loss of use, loss of profits, loss of business opportunity, loss of data, loss of goodwill or reputation whether in an action in contract, tort, for tortious or contractual negligence, or otherwise, arising out of or in any way connected with the use or inability to use this website or the materials contained in, or accessed through, this website. This does not apply to any liability we may have towards you in respect of goods and services that we sell or supply to you.

Other than as set out above in this section, we shall not be liable to you for any loss and damage which is not a reasonably foreseeable consequence of your use of this website and purchase of goods and services in accordance with these Site Terms.

If you are not a Consumer, our maximum aggregate liability to you in respect of goods and services that you purchase from us via the website (whether in contract, tort including negligence, strict liability, breach of statutory duty or other legal theory) shall be limited to the price charged to you in relation to those goods and services.

Nothing in this section shall operate to exclude or limit in any way our liability for personal injury or death caused by our negligence or our liability for fraud.

#### O. GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION

These Site Terms shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of England and Wales. Regardless of where you access this website, you agree that any claim or other legal action in law or in equity arising out of or relating to the Site Terms shall be determined only in the courts of England and Wales, and you hereby irrevocably and unconditionally consent and submit to the exclusive jurisdiction and venue of such courts over any suit, action or proceeding arising out of the Site Terms.

#### Q. TERMINATION

Notwithstanding the Site Terms, we reserve the right, without notice and in our sole discretion, to terminate your licence to use this website, and to block or prevent future access to and use of this website if you breach any of the Site Terms or applicable law. Upon termination, these Site Terms shall still apply.

#### R. SEVERABILITY AND WAIVERS

If any provision of the Site Terms is found to be unlawful, void, or unenforceable, then that provision shall be deemed to be severed from the rest of the Site Terms and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any and all remaining provisions.

No waiver by us shall be construed as a waiver of any proceeding or succeeding breach of any and all provisions documented within the Site Terms. All waivers shall be made in writing.

#### S. THIRD PARTY RIGHTS

No party who is not a party to the agreement between us created by the Site Terms (other than Costco's subsidiaries and affiliates) shall have any right to enforce any of the Site Terms whether by virtue of the Contracts (Rights of Third Parties) Act 1999 or otherwise.

#### T. FURTHER INFORMATION 

For further information about Consumer statutory rights, please see our Consumer Fact Sheet: U.K. Statutory Cancellation Right or visit [www.adviceguide.org.uk](http://www.adviceguide.org.uk/). 

#### U. CONTACT US

If you experience difficulties in using the website or wish to report any matter relating to this website, please contact us:   
By phone: freephone number **0800 0324 324**.   
By e-mail: [customercare@costco.co.uk](mailto:customercare@costco.co.uk).  
By mail: Costco.co.uk, Building 4400 Harris Parkway Magna Park Lutterworth LE17 4XJ 

#### EXHIBIT A

Currently, the registered trade marks owned by the Costco Companies include the following without limitation: BANQUET, GRANDMA PORCOS, COSTCO, COSTCO.CO.UK, COSTCO CONCIERGE SERVICES, THE COSTCO CONNECTION, COSTCO WHOLESALE, KIRKLAND, SIGNATURE, COSTCO WHOLESALE EXECUTIVE MEMBER, KIRKLAND SIGNATURE, CHOCOLATES OF THE WORLD, COURT CLASSIC, and FUNHOUSE TREATS. The Costco Companies also may use other trade marks that are not registered. 

## Statutory Cancellation Rights 

#### What is my statutory cancellation right as a consumer?

In most circumstances, Costco’s return policy provides consumers with the most favourable return privileges available.  Under the UK's Consumer Protection Regulations of 2013 (as amended) (the "Regulations") , however, you have an additional, statutory right to cancel orders for goods and services made through the website. This right ("statutory cancellation right") applies only where you make your purchase as a Consumer. You can only use this right within a period of 14 days. The period of 14 days begins on the day after the day on which you receive the goods relating to your order or (in the case of services) the day after the day on which the contract is concluded.

#### Are there any exceptions to the statutory cancellation right?

The statutory cancellation right also does not apply to certain types of goods, namely:

  * goods that have been personalised or otherwise made to your specifications;
  * goods such as flowers, food, plants or other goods which by their nature are liable to deteriorate or expire rapidly or cannot be returned (such as pierced jewellery), underwear or swimming costumes where the hygiene strips or seals have been removed);
  * audio or video recordings or computer software that has been unsealed;
  * newspapers, periodicals or magazines; or
  * goods where the price is dependent on fluctuations in the financial market (such as vintage wines).

The statutory cancellation right does not apply to certain kinds of services, or to any kind of service that has been fully performed where (by your express request) performance has begun before the end of the cancellation period.

#### What are my obligations?

Costco requires customers using the statutory cancellation right to return the goods to Costco in the event of cancellation. Costco also requires customers using the statutory cancellation right to pay the cost of returning them, or the cost incurred by Costco in recovering them.

#### How do I exercise my statutory cancellation right?

If you wish to exercise your statutory cancellation right please contact our Customer Care Centre at freephone **0800 0324 324** or by email, fax or hand/postal delivery to the address here; Customer Care Manager, Costco Online UK Ltd., UK Home Office, Hartspring Lane, Watford, WD25 8JS, United Kingdom. Alternatively, you can complete our cancellation form which is available **[here](http://warehouses.costco.co.uk/_docs/CostcoUK_Cancellation_Form.doc)** and send this to us by email, fax or hand/postal delivery to the address above.

#### What must I do with the goods?

Customers using the statutory cancellation right are required to return the goods to us (in their original packaging, wherever possible) as soon as possible and in any event within 14 days after the day you informed us that you wish to cancel their order, and in the manner we direct. For items that, due to their nature cannot be returned by post, you should contact us for information about the cost of return shipping.

Costco will instruct you how to make the returns to us. We may ask you to send the item to us using labels that we will provide. Alternatively, we may arrange for our carrier to collect them from you within five days following your notifying us of your wish to return the goods. You may request a later collection date, and we will accommodate you if circumstances permit.

#### When should I expect my refund?

If you exercise your statutory cancellation right we will reimburse you within 14 days following the day on which we receive the goods from you. Refunds will be made in the same way as your original payment.

Please note that this is not a full statement of your statutory cancellation right. For further information, please consult [www.adviceguide.org.uk](http://www.adviceguide.org.uk/).

## WEEE Regulations

#### Waste Electrical and Electronic Equipment (WEEE) Business-to-Business use

This agreement applies to businesses who buy products on www.costco.co.uk and covers the WEEE regulations in force in the United Kingdom since 2006. These regulations may be amended from time to time.

This agreement applies to relevant electrical and electronic equipment (EEE), which has been purchased from Costco Online UK Ltd by its Trade members, and other purchasers that are not for private households.

The buyer of this relevant EEE acknowledges and agrees that the buyer shall:

  1. At all times be and remain responsible for the collection, treatment, recovery and environmentally sound disposal of relevant WEEE and all associated financial charges.
  2. Have its own arrangements in place for dealing with the relevant WEEE in a way that is consistent with the WEEE regulations and continue to comply with all WEEE regulations.
  3. Provide Costco Online UK Ltd with such co-operation, assistance and information as may be reasonably required in relation to WEEE. The information will be used for Costco Online UK Ltd obligations under the WEEE regulations.

#### Recycling your old electricals is easy!

Recycle your electrical and electronic devices free at your local recycling centre. To find your nearest centre, visit the [Recycle More](http://www.recycle-more.co.uk/) website and type in your postcode.

#### Why recycle?

Unwanted electrical equipment is the UK's fastest growing type of waste.

Many electrical items can be repaired or recycled, saving natural resources and the environment. If you do not recycle electrical equipment will end up in landfill where hazardous substances will leak out and cause soil and water contamination – harming wildlife and also human health.

We're proud to support your local authority in providing local recycling facilities for electrical equipment.

To remind you that old electrical equipment can be recycled, it is now marked with the crossed-out wheeled bin symbol. Please do not throw any electrical equipment (including those marked with this symbol) in your bin.

#### How are we helping?

In the UK, distributors including retailers must provide a system which allows all customers buying new electrical equipment the opportunity to recycle their old items free of charge. As a responsible retailer, we have met the requirements placed on us by financially supporting the national network of WEEE recycling centres established by local authorities. This is achieved through membership of the national Distributor Take-back scheme (DTS).

To find more information on WEEE recycling and to locate your nearest recycling centre please visit the [Recycle More](http://www.recycle-more.co.uk/) website.
